Chinemerem David Ezeakudolu

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

David is an organized solution-driven software developer with excellent coding, debugging, and problem-solving skills, he has +5 years' experience in providing quality code that follows software development standards and methodologies, this includes design, development, and unit testing of solutions. David possesses the passion to be involved in the advancement of technology which fuels his self-drive to be a continuous learner improving his knowledge about computer programming and other data science fundamentals not only by receiving advice from more experienced professionals and but also by facing and solving real life challenging issues. David specializes in full stack development utilizing the MERN (Mongo, Express, React Node.js) stack for majority of his projects and work experiences, he also has a strong understanding of C#, Java and Swift Javascript and Python being his stand outs and most comfortable languages.

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

(+5 years): **Frontend development** (React Angular) – Proficient understanding of client-side scripting and JavaScript/TypeScript frameworks. Experience with responsive and adaptive user interface design. Good experience with SQL and relational databases. Ability to quickly learn and apply new technologies. Experience with technologies like Yarn, NPM, Jira, Kanban, Jest, Gitlab and Confluence. Create and optimize web app interfaces,in a simple, clear, and intuitive way using the latest technologies in Saas and CSS to allow the platform to stand out.

(+4 years): **Backend development** (Python/Django Node.js PHP Java Git SQL/NoSQL Firebase) Familiarity using Scrum/Agile development methodologies. Comfortable with Git for source control. Solid experience with JavaScript unit and feature testing concepts and frameworks. Consuming and creating backend RESTful APIs. Analyze develop and test features. between multiple systems and environments. Strong understanding of cross-browser compatibility development and testing concepts.

(+2 years): **Data Science** (Python Pandas NumPy ML Algorithms Sckit-learn) Deep Knowledge of math, probability, statistics, and algorithms. Ability to write robust code in python. Leverage distributed computing, machine learning and artificial intelligence techniques for analysis, data mining and modeling. Developing prediction systems and machine learning algorithms.

A problem solver with eagerness to learn and work as a member of a team with commitment to on-time top quality solution delivery good knowledge of the following working environments: (VSCode, WordPress Xcode Visual Studio Unity). Confidence and skill to communicate ideas in a clear, detail-oriented manner showcasing self-drive.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Evenica Corp, Application Developer

May 2022

- Build and extend functionality for both Dynamics 365 Commerce and Evenica's in house Ecommerce platform, using C#, TypeScript, SQL, Angular, React.js, Redux, Ngrx, HTML and CSS
- Follow development processes, conduct code reviews, manage code repositories, interact with the Support/QA teams.
- Design and document user interfaces to cater to a variety of business requirements
- Design and document database models to cater to a variety of business requirements
- Develop integrations of cloud-based systems using web services and using API,

Journey Education, Full Stack Web Developer Instructor

September 2021 – April 2022

- Tutored over 600+ hours of frontend, backend and various software development and web development topics.
- Worked closely with other instructors and members of the education team to ensure best practices are performed for the enhancement of all student's knowledge.
- Assigned course work, grading, and mentoring students in smaller groups and on 1-1 basis.
- Developed various websites, APIs, and projects solutions for students' utilizing JavaScript, React, Node.js, MongoDB along with development tools such as GitHub, Visual Studio code and others.
- Have a direct positive impact on changing people's lives through education
- Worked remotely and attended various online meetings to create a collaborative environment and present project proposals with supervisors and other team members.

BorderWorx Logistics, WordPress Web Designer

August 2021- February 2022

- Implemented, responsive design and web pages using WordPress CMS.
- Designed and managed the website back-end including database and server integration.

- Worked with marketing and research teams to incorporate brand elements and relevant market research findings into websites.
- Ensured website function and stability across devices to enhance better user experience and user interface (UI / UX) i.e., desktop, mobile, tablet.
- Employed industry and design guidelines, standards, and best practice through website build process.
- Analyze code and improve design, performance, and security
- Responsible for ensuring the quality of the application, fixing application bugs, maintaining the code, and implemented application updates.

Mohawk College, Front End Developer

July 2020 – February 2021

- Designed and developed different projects with a group of team members.
- Built reusable code for future use that determines the structure and design of web pages and ensured enhanced user experience on all devices.
- Created an interactive website using MySQL database and PHP for the back-end integration as well as HTML5 Javascript, Bootstrap, XML, JSON, GraphQL and CSS for front-end implementation.
- Worked remotely and attended various online meetings to discuss and present project status with supervisors and other team members.
- Provided documentations as appropriate, including design documents, comments in code, software requirement specifications and end-user documentation.

Industry-Education Council, Web Developer/Tutor

September 2019 – December 2019

- Gained hands-on experience with WordPress to design the company's website.
- Enrolled students in an intensive 4-month web development HTML jQuery, JavaScript, DOM, SASS
- Tutored over 200+ office hours, going above and beyond with interactive projects to keep students involved and interested.
- Inspired students to develop an interest and appreciate value in Computer Science and technology as well as share their passion with others.
- Assisted students on their weekly labs to give them a strong understanding of the concept.
- Developed various web programs as projects for the students attending the program.

ACTIVITIES AND VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

WordPress Developer, City of David

July 2021

- Developed robust, responsive WordPress themes for over the client.
- Managed and designed a responsive website for a church committee with over 2000 members.

Game Development Club, Mohawk College

August 2018 – December 2021

- Created basic multiplayer games using C# in the Unity environments.
- Attended over 100+ hours learning game development aspects with interactive lessons and projects.

Cyber Security Awareness, Mohawk College

September 2018 – December 2018

• Attended over 100+ study hours understanding cyber security threats networks face and the risks they introduce their end users to.

EDUCATION

Advanced Diploma Computer Systems Technology – Software Development Mohawk College, Hamilton, ON

Graduated April 2021

- Academic Honors: Certification of Hard work and Excellence, Dean's List (2 Semesters), GPA: 3.6/4 Course Completed:
 - Android and IOS Development (Swift, Java)
 - Web Development (PHP, JavaScript, React Vue, Node.js)
 - Software Engineering Management
 - Software Quality and Testing
 - Machine Learning

- Database Management Systems
- Java Programing and Data Structures
- Object-oriented Programming
- Mathematics for Computer Science
- Introduction to Networking.

AWARDS AND ACHIVEMENTS

- Dean's List 2019 at Mohawk College.
- Certification of Hard work and Excellence at Mohawk College.
- Certification of Completion for Building Advanced Modern Projects with Azure.
- Certification of Completion for ASP.NET Core: Payment Gateways.
- Amazon Web Services (AWS) Certification.